Register of the Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych Records, 1919-1947.
Hoover Institution Archives
- SERIES NO. 410. TELEGRAMS BETWEEN MINISTRY AND POLAND'S FOREIGN REPRESENTATIONS.
  - 1943
    - Embassies
      - Washington
        - General
          - September (Box 274)
            - Outgoing (Folder 2)
          - October
            - Incoming (Folder 3)
            - Outgoing (Folder 4)
          - November
            - Incoming (Folder 5)
            - Outgoing (Folder 6)
          - December
            - Incoming (Folder 7)
            - Outgoing (Folder 8)
        - Top secret
          - Incoming (Folder 9)
          - Outgoing (Folder 10)
      - Wellington
        - General
          - Incoming (Folder 11)
          - Outgoing (Folder 12)
        - Top secret. Incoming (Folder 13)
      - Winnipeg
        - Incoming (Folder 14)
        - Outgoing (Folder 15)
  - 1945
    - General
      - Circulars (Folder 16)
      - Instructions on telegram coding (Folder 17)
      - Poufny biuletyn informacyjny (Folder 18)
    - Embassies
      - Algiers, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 19)
        - Outgoing (Folder 20)
      - Ankara, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 21)
        - Outgoing (Folder 22)
      - Athens, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 23)
        - Outgoing (Folder 24)
      - Baghdad
        - Incoming, Jan.-Apr. (Folder 25)
        - Outgoing, Jan.-May (Folder 26)
      - Bern (Box 275)
        - Jan.-March
          - Incoming (Folder 1)
          - Outgoing (Folder 2)
        - Apr.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 3)
          - Outgoing (Folder 4)
      - Beirut
        - Jan.-March
          - Incoming (Folder 5)
          - Outgoing (Folder 6)
        - Apr.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 7)
          - Outgoing (Folder 8)
      - Bogota, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 9)
        - Outgoing (Folder 10)
      - Bombay, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 11)
        - Outgoing (Folder 12)
      - Brussels, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 13)
        - Outgoing (Folder 14)
      - Buenos Aires, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 15)
        - Outgoing (Folder 16)
      - Cairo, Jan.-May (Box 276)
        - Embassy
          - Incoming (Folder 1)
          - Outgoing (Folder 2)
        - Ministerstwo Stanu
          - Incoming (Folder 3)
          - Outgoing (Folder 4)
      - Cape Town, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 5)
        - Outgoing (Folder 6)
      - Chicago, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 7)
        - Outgoing (Folder 8)
      - Chungking, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 9)
        - Outgoing (Folder 10)
      - Curitiba, Jan.-March
        - Incoming (Folder 11)
        - Outgoing (Folder 12)
      - Dar es Salaam
        - Incoming, Jan.-Feb. (Folder 13)
        - Outgoing, Jan.-March (Folder 14)
      - Detroit. Incoming, March-May (Folder 15)
      - Dublin. Incoming, June (Folder 16)
      - Havana, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 17)
        - Outgoing (Folder 18)
      - Istanbul
        - Jan.-March
          - Incoming (Folder 19)
          - Outgoing (Folder 20)
        - Apr.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 21)
          - Outgoing (Folder 22)
      - Jerusalem
        - January
          - Incoming (Folder 23)
          - Outgoing (Folder 24)
        - February
          - Incoming (Folder 25)
          - Outgoing (Folder 26)
        - March (Box 277)
          - Incoming (Folder 1)
          - Outgoing (Folder 2)
        - April
          - Incoming (Folder 3)
          - Outgoing (Folder 4)
        - May
          - Incoming (Folder 5)
          - Outgoing (Folder 6)
      - Johannesburg, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 7)
        - Outgoing (Folder 8)
      - Kampala. Incoming, February (Folder 9)
      - Lima, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 10)
        - Outgoing (Folder 11)
      - Lisbon
        - Jan.-March
          - Incoming (Folder 12)
          - Outgoing (Folder 13)
        - Apr.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 14)
          - Outgoing (Folder 15)
      - Lusaca, Feb.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 16)
        - Outgoing (Folder 17)
      - Madrid, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 18)
        - Outgoing (Folder 19)
      - Mexico City, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 20)
        - Outgoing (Folder 21)
      - Montevideo, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 22)
        - Outgoing (Folder 23)
      - Montreal, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 24)
        - Outgoing (Folder 25)
      - Nairobi, Jan.-May (Box 278)
        - Incoming (Folder 1)
        - Outgoing (Folder 2)
      - New York
        - Jan.-March
          - Incoming (Folder 3)
          - Outgoing (Folder 4)
        - Apr.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 5)
          - Outgoing (Folder 6)
      - Ottawa, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 7)
        - Outgoing (Folder 8)
      - Paris
        - Embassy
          - January
            - Incoming (Folder 9)
            - Outgoing (Folder 10)
          - February
            - Incoming (Folder 11)
            - Outgoing (Folder 12)
          - March
            - Incoming (Folder 13)
            - Outgoing (Folder 14)
          - April
            - Incoming (Folder 15)
            - Outgoing (Folder 16)
          - May (Box 279)
            - Incoming (Folder 1)
            - Outgoing (Folder 2)
        - S.H.A.E.F. (Supreme Headquarters Allied Expeditionary Forces), Apr.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 3)
          - Outgoing (Folder 4)
      - Pittsburgh, March-May. Incoming (Folder 5)
      - Rio de Janeiro, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 6)
        - Outgoing (Folder 7)
      - Rome
        - Consulate, Jan.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 8)
          - Outgoing (Folder 9)
        - Embassy, Jan.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 10)
          - Outgoing (Folder 11)
      - Salisbury, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 12)
        - Outgoing (Folder 13)
      - San Francisco
        - Incoming, Apr.-May (Folder 14)
        - Outgoing, Feb.-May (Folder 15)
      - Santiago de Chile, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 16)
        - Outgoing (Folder 17)
      - Stockholm
        - Jan.-March
          - Incoming (Folder 18)
          - Outgoing (Folder 19)
        - Apr.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 20)
          - Outgoing (Folder 21)
      - Sydney, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 22)
        - Outgoing (Folder 23)
      - Teheran (Box 280)
        - January
          - Incoming (Folder 1)
          - Outgoing (Folder 2)
        - February
          - Incoming (Folder 3)
          - Outgoing (Folder 4)
        - March
          - Incoming (Folder 5)
          - Outgoing (Folder 6)
        - April
          - Incoming (Folder 7)
          - Outgoing (Folder 8)
        - May
          - Incoming (Folder 9)
          - Outgoing (Folder 10)
      - Tel Aviv, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 11)
        - Outgoing (Folder 12)
      - Vatican
        - Jan.-March
          - Incoming (Folder 13)
          - Outgoing (Folder 14)
        - Apr.-May
          - Incoming (Folder 15)
          - Outgoing (Folder 16)
      - Washington
        - January
          - Incoming (Folder 17)
          - Outgoing (Folder 18)
        - February (Box 281)
          - Incoming (Folder 1)
          - Outgoing (Folder 2)
        - March
          - Incoming (Folder 3)
          - Outgoing (Folder 4)
        - April
          - Incoming (Folder 5)
          - Outgoing (Folder 6)
        - May
          - Incoming (Folder 7)
          - Outgoing (Folder 8)
      - Wellington, Jan.-May
        - Incoming (Folder 9)
        - Outgoing (Folder 10)
      - Winnipeg
        - Incoming, February (Folder 11)
        - Outgoing, January (Folder 12)
- SERIES NO. 413. NOTIFICATIONS. 1939.
  Formation of new government, October-December
  - General. Circular to embassies, October (Box 282, Folder 1)
  - Countries
    - Afghanistan (Folder 2)
    - Argentina (Folder 3)
    - Belgium (Folder 4)
    - Brazil (Folder 5)
    - Bulgaria (Folder 6)
    - Canada (Folder 7)
    - Chile (Folder 8)
    - China (Folder 9)
    - Colombia (Folder 10)
    - Cuba (Folder 11)
    - Denmark (Folder 12)
    - Egypt (Folder 13)
    - Finland (Folder 14)
    - France (Folder 15)
    - Great Britain
      - General (Folder 16)
      - Dominions (Folder 17)
    - Greece (Folder 18)
    - Guatemala (Folder 19)
    - Haiti (Folder 20)
    - Hungary (Folder 21)
    - Iran (Folder 22)
    - Japan (Folder 23)
    - Latvia (Folder 24)
    - Lithuania (Folder 25)
    - Mexico City (Folder 26)
    - Netherlands (Folder 27)
    - Norway (Folder 28)
    - Panama (Folder 29)
    - Portugal (Folder 30)
    - Romania (Folder 31)
    - Spain (Folder 32)
    - Sweden (Folder 33)
    - Switzerland (Folder 34)
    - Turkey (Folder 35)
    - United States (Folder 36)
    - Uruguay (Folder 37)
    - Vatican (Folder 38)
    - Yugoslavia (Folder 39)
- SERIES NO. 414. VISITS
  - 1939. Welles, Sumner. Trip to Paris, March (Folder 40)
  - 1940. Haller, Jozef. Trip to the United States, Jan.-May (Folder 41)
- SERIES NO. 416. MEDALS AND DECORATIONS. 1944.
  - Golden Cross of Merit, List of candidates for (Folder 42)
- SERIES NO. 417. INFORMATION BANK ON "CORPS DIPLOMATIQUE"
  - 1934
    - General. Circular on Information Bank (Folder 43)
    - Helsinki (Folder 44)
    - Lisbon (Folder 45)
    - Madrid (Folder 46)
    - Vatican (Folder 47)
    - Warsaw (Folder 48)
  - 1935. Vatican (Folder 49)
- SERIES NO. 420. PRESIDENT OF POLISH REPUBLIC
  - Presidential speech to Lord Mayor of London, Mansion House, April 8th, 1943 (Folder 50)
  - Telegrams to President
    - 1942
      - May (Folder 51)
      - June (Folder 52)
      - July (Folder 53)
      - August (Box 283, Folder 1)
      - September (Folder 2)
      - October (Folder 3)
      - November (Folder 4)
      - December (Folder 5)
    - 1943
      - January (Folder 6)
      - February (Folder 7)
      - March (Folder 8)
      - April (Folder 9)
      - May (Folder 10)
      - June (Folder 11)
      - July (Folder 12)
      - August (Folder 13)
      - September (Folder 14)
      - October (Folder 15)
      - November (Folder 16)
      - December (Folder 17)
    - 1944 (Box 284)
      - January (Folder 1)
      - February (Folder 2)
      - March (Folder 3)
      - April (Folder 4)
      - May (Folder 5)
      - June (Folder 6)
      - July (Folder 7)
      - August (Folder 8)
      - September (Folder 9)
      - October (Folder 10)
      - November (Folder 11)
      - December (Folder 12)
    - 1945
      - January (Folder 13)
      - February (Folder 14)
      - March (Folder 15)
      - April (Folder 16)
      - May (Folder 17)
      - June (Folder 18)
- SERIES NO. 421. MARSHAL JOZEF PILSUDSKI, 1930.
  - Trip to Madera. Telegrams, reports (Folder 19)
- SERIES NO. 422. ORGANIZATION OF DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR RELATIONS, 1940.
  - "Rocznik Sluzby Zagranicznej", Angers. Mimeograph (Folder 20)
- SERIES NO. 423. PERSONNEL OF EMBASSIES AND CONSULATES
  - 1943. Ministry's London headquarters. Organizational scheme (Folder 21)
  - 1944
    - Ministry's London headquarters
      - Foreign representations in London. List of staff (Folder 22)
      - Staff hired during war time. List (Folder 23)
    - Payroll
      - Embassies and consulates (Folder 24)
      - Pay categories (Folder 25)
    - Polish foreign representations. List (Folder 26)
- SERIES NO. 424. DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR WORK, 1944.
  - "Zestawienie porownawcze". Directives for Supreme Headquarters Allied Expeditionary Forces liaison officers. Charts, typescripts (Box 285, Folder 1)
- SERIES NO. 436. ORGANIZATIONAL STATUTES
  - 1932 (Folder 2)
  - 1940 (Folder 3)
- SERIES NO. 437. INTERNAL REGULATIONS AND INSTRUCTIONS
  - 1930. Zbior przepisow konsularnych, part 3. Collected consular regulations. Printed copy (Folder 4)
  - 1943 (Folder 5)
- SERIES NO. 438. ORGANIZATIONAL REGULATIONS
  - 1940 (Folder 6)
  - 1941 (Folder 7)
  - 1942
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Instructions and circulars (Folder 9)
  - 1944 (Folder 10)
- SERIES NO. 439. CIRCULARS
  - 1940 (Folder 11)
  - 1942 (Folder 12)
  - 1943
    - General (Folder 13)
    - Mimeographs (Folder 14)
  - 1945 (Folder 15)
- SERIES NO. 470. APPLICATIONS FOR ADMISSION TO STATE SERVICES
  - 1924 (Box 286, Folder 1)
  - 1941 (Folder 2)
  - 1942 (Folder 3)
  - 1943 (Folder 4)
  - 1944. Candidates for positions
    - First and second category (Folder 5)
    - Lower (Folder 6)
- SERIES NO. 472. DISCIPLINARY INVESTIGATIONS
  - 1932. Government decrees on disciplinary courts (Folder 7)
  - 1939
    - Charwat, Franciszek. Disciplinary commission protocol (Folder 8)
    - Dubicz-Penther, Karol. Protocol of disciplinary commission. Proceedings (Folder 9)
  - 1940
    - Charwat, Franciszek
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Verdict (Folder 11)
    - Marchlewski, Mieczyslaw, Case against (Folder 12)
    - Szumlakowski, M.
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Miranda de Ebro concentration camp. Fate of Polish prisoners of war (Folder 14)
  - 1941
    - Charwat, Franciszek. Appeal (Folder 15)
    - Dalbeth Convent incident (Folder 16)
    - Dubicz-Penther, Karol
      - Letter to minister (Folder 17)
      - Testimonies against (Folder 18)
    - Ganz, Jan, Case of (Folder 19)
    - Marchlewski, Mieczyslaw. General (Folder 20)
    - Orlowski, Karol, Case and testimony of (Folder 21)
    - Schmitzek, Stanislaw (Folder 22)
    - Szumlakowski, M.
      - General (Folder 23)
      - Miranda de Ebro concentration camp (Folder 24)
      - 1942 (Box 287)
    - Charwat, Franciszek
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Appeal commission (Folder 2)
      - Documents submitted to minister (Folder 3)
    - Couriers
      - Gantkowski (Folder 4)
      - Radziwill, Wladyslaw (Folder 5)
    - Marchlewski, Mieczyslaw
      - Case report, enclosures, testimonies (Folder 6)
      - Witnesses reports (Folder 7)
    - Mohl, Aleksander, Case against (Folder 8)
    - Schmitzek, Stanislaw-Marlewski, Jozef (Folder 9)
    - Strakacz, Sylwin-Kwapiszewski case
      - Correspondence and telegrams (Folder 10)
      - Investigation commission. Case report
        - General (Folder 11)
        - Enclosures (Folder 12)
    - Szumlakowski, Marian
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Konarek, Czeslaw, Case of (Folder 14)
      - Miranda de Ebro concentration camp (Folder 15)
  - 1943
    - Charwat, Franciszek. Trial documents (Folder 16)
    - Dubicz-Penther, Karol
      - General (Folder 17)
      - Appeal (Folder 18)
      - Hearing protocol (Box 288, Folder 1)
      - Proceedings of disciplinary commission (Folder 2)
      - Testimonies of witnesses (Folder 3)
      - Verdict (Folder 4)
    - Members of disciplinary commission (Folder 5)
    - Mohl, Aleksander (Folder 6)
    - Pawlowicz, Czeslaw (Folder 7)
    - Schmitzek, Stanislaw-Marlewski, Jozef (Folder 8)
    - Strakacz, Sylwin-Kwapiszewski. Correspondence, telegrams (Folder 9)
    - Szumlakowski, Marian
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Correspondence from (Folder 11)
      - Investigation Commission. Protocols, verdict (Folder 12)
      - Ministry of Defense. Reports, testimonies (Folder 13)
      - Testimonies against (Folder 14)
      - Transition of responsibilities (Folder 15)
  - 1944
    - Dubicz-Penther, Karol. Appeal (Folder 16)
    - Kamerman, Emil (Box 289, Folder 1)
    - Ripa, Karol
      - Case report. Enclosures (Folder 2)
      - Charges against (Folder 3)
      - Consulates financial report, Oct. 24 (Folder 4)
      - Correspondence from (Folder 5)
      - Public response to his case (Folder 6)
      - Response to charges (Folder 7)
      - Telegrams from (Folder 8)
    - Schmitzek, Stanislaw-Marlewski, Jozef (Folder 9)
    - Strakacz, Sylwin-Kwapiszewski
      - Correspondence and telegrams (Folder 10)
      - Trial protocol (Folder 11)
      - Verdict (Folder 12)
    - Szumlakowski, Marian
      - General (Folder 13)
      - Consulate. Transition of responsibilities
        - January (Folder 14)
        - February (Folder 15)
        - March
          - General (Folder 16)
          - Report and inventories (Folder 17)
  - 1945 (Box 290)
    - Ripa, Karol
      - Correspondence from (Folder 1)
      - Findings of investigation commission (Folder 2)
    - Strakacz, Sylwin-Kwapiszewski. Correspondence (Folder 3)
    - Szumlakowski, Marian
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Lisiewicz, Adam, Report of (Folder 5)
- SERIES NO. 473. VACATIONS
  - 1943 (Folder 6)
  - 1944 (Folder 7)
- SERIES NO. 474. OFFICE CLERKS
  - 1931. Instructions for job application forms (Folder 8)
  - 1940. Angers, Jan.-June
    - General
      - Appointments, transfers (Folder 9)
      - Ministry employees list (Folder 10)
    - Employees. Individual files
      - Arciszewski (Folder 11)
      - Chalupczynski (Folder 12)
      - Chodosowska, Wiktoria (Folder 13)
      - Ciechanowski, Jan (Folder 14)
      - Czarnowski, Wincenty (Folder 15)
      - Czudowski, Michal (Folder 16)
      - Dobrowolska, Jadwiga (Folder 17)
      - Drymer, W. F. (Folder 18)
      - Englisch, Aleksander (Folder 19)
      - Fryling, Jan (Folder 20)
      - Gubrynowicz, Z. (Folder 21)
      - Gwiazdowski, T. (Folder 22)
      - Hryniewicz (Folder 23)
      - Illakowiczowna, Kazimiera (Folder 24)
      - Jazdzewski (Folder 25)
      - Juchniewiczowa, Bronislawa (Folder 26)
      - Karszo-Siedlecki (Folder 27)
      - Komarnicki, Tytus (Folder 28)
      - Koppens, L. (Folder 29)
      - Koscialkowski, Waclaw (Folder 30)
      - Lados, Aleksander (Folder 31)
      - Laube, Waclaw (Folder 32)
      - Litwinski, Leon (Folder 33)
      - Loret, Adam (Folder 34)
      - Lubienski, Aleksander (Folder 35)
      - Mazurkiewicz, Wladyslaw (Folder 36)
      - Merdinger (Folder 37)
      - Meysztowicz (Folder 38)
      - Mieczyslawski (Folder 39)
      - Moscicki, Jozef (Folder 40)
      - Papee, Kazimierz (Folder 41)
      - Pilch, Tadeusz (Folder 42)
      - Potocki, Jerzy (Folder 43)
      - Raczynski, Roger (Folder 44)
      - Ripa, Karol (Folder 45)
      - Rolski (Folder 46)
      - Samborski, Bohdan (Folder 47)
      - Strakacz, Sylwin (Folder 48)
      - Swiniarska (Folder 49)
      - Szumlakowski, Marian (Folder 50)
      - Szumowski (Folder 51)
      - Szymanska, Halina (Folder 52)
      - Szymanska, Jadwiga (Folder 53)
      - Tarnowski, Adam (Folder 54)
      - Wankowicz, Witold (Folder 55)
      - Zabiello, Janina (Folder 56)
      - Zaleski, Maciej (Folder 57)
      - Zaranski (Folder 58)
      - Zoltowski, Adam (Folder 59)
  - 1940. London, July-Dec. Fundusz Pomocy Kolezenskiej (Mutual Assistance Fund)
    - Back pay for September 1939 (Folder 60)
    - Former employees residing in Poland (Folder 61)
    - Payments list (Folder 62)
    - Receipts (Folder 63)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 291)
    - Military service. Exemption (Folder 1)
    - Personnel issues (Folder 2)
    - Staff on leave
      - General (Folder 3)
      - A-C (Folder 4)
      - D-Gos (Folder 5)
      - Gralinski family (Folder 6)
      - Gra-Grz (Folder 7)
      - H-J (Folder 8)
      - Ka-Kop (Folder 9)
      - Korsak, Witold Adam (Folder 10)
      - Kos-Kw (Folder 11)
      - L-M (Folder 12)
      - N-P (Folder 13)
      - R-St (Folder 14)
      - Szawlowski, Andrzej (Box 292, Folder 1)
      - Sze-T (Folder 2)
      - W-Za (Folder 3)
      - Zaleski, August (Folder 4)
  - 1941
    - Back pay for September 1939 (Folder 5)
    - Embassies and consulates
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Budget (Folder 7)
      - Diplomatic corps in London (Folder 8)
    - Fundusz Pomocy Kolezenskiej (Mutual Assistance Fund)
      - Accounts of receipts (Folder 9)
      - Former employees
        - General (Folder 10)
        - List (Folder 11)
      - France
        - General (Folder 12)
        - Employees and their families (Folder 13)
      - Payment lists (Folder 14)
      - Receipts
        - Jan.-June (Folder 15)
        - July-Dec. (Folder 16)
    - Ministry
      - Staff list (Folder 17)
      - Organizational scheme. Mimeographed circular (Folder 18)
    - Payroll, July (Folder 19)
    - 1942 (Box 293)
    - Back pay for September 1939 (Folder 1)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (Folder 2)
    - Embassies and consulates
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Africa. Consular network (Folder 4)
      - Ankara Embassy (Folder 5)
      - Budget (Folder 6)
      - Kuibyshev Embassy (Folder 7)
      - Staff (Folder 8)
    - Fundusz Pomocy Kolezenskiej (Mutual Assistance Fund)
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Accounts of receipts (Folder 10)
      - Former employees
        - General (Folder 11)
        - List (Folder 12)
      - France (Folder 13)
      - Ministry employees as prisoners of war (Folder 14)
      - Payment list (Folder 15)
      - Receipts (Folder 16)
    - Home Guards, Volunteers for (Folder 17)
    - Korwin, Marta affair (Folder 18)
    - Military service. Exemptions
      - Consulates employees. Great Britain (Folder 19)
      - London Embassy (Folder 20)
      - Ministry Headquarters (Folder 21)
    - Ministerial decrees (Folder 22)
    - Personal data (Folder 23)
    - Personnel issues
      - General (Folder 24)
      - Clothing rationing coupons (Box 294, Folder 1)
      - Coding department. Overtime work (Folder 2)
      - Employee registration forms (Folder 3)
      - Recipients (Folder 4)
      - Supplementary family payments (Folder 5)
    - Staff on leave
      - General (Folder 6)
      - A-Bra (Folder 7)
      - Brodzki, Jan (Folder 8)
      - C (Folder 9)
      - D-G (Folder 10)
      - H-K (Folder 11)
      - L-P (Folder 12)
      - R-S (Folder 13)
      - T-Z (Folder 14)
    - "Ustawa o panstwowej sluzbie cywilnej". Decree on state civil service by Biuro Prac Administracyjnych. Mimeograph (Folder 15)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 295)
    - Appointments, transfers, dismissals
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Arciszewski (Folder 2)
      - Arlet, Wieslaw (Folder 3)
      - Aszkenazy, Natalia (Folder 4)
      - Domaniewski (Folder 5)
      - Drobniak (Folder 6)
      - Drohojowski, Jan (Folder 7)
      - Drymmer, Wiktor Tomir (Folder 8)
      - Dubicz-Penther, Karol (Folder 9)
      - Glaser, Stefan (Folder 10)
      - Kedzior (Folder 11)
      - Korsak-Kanski (Folder 12)
      - Kunicki (Folder 13)
      - Leitgeber, Gerda (Folder 14)
      - Lubaczewski (Folder 15)
      - Lecki, Waclaw (Folder 16)
      - Marchlewski, Mieczyslaw (Folder 17)
      - Potocki, Jozef (Folder 18)
      - Raczynski, Edward (Folder 19)
      - Romer, Tadeusz (Folder 20)
      - Rozwadowski (Russanowski), Karol (Folder 21)
      - Sokolnicki-Stronski-Bader-Mniszek-Karszo-Siedlecki (Folder 22)
      - Sosnkowski, Kazimierz (Folder 23)
      - Szumlakowski, Marian (Folder 24)
      - Wieniawa-Dlugoszowski, Boleslaw (Folder 25)
      - Wierusz-Kowalski (Folder 26)
      - Zawadowski, Witold (Folder 27)
      - Zazulinski (Folder 28)
  - 1943
    - General (Folder 29)
    - Appointments and transfers
      - General (Folder 30)
      - Middle East (Folder 31)
    - Embassies and consulates
      - Bombay Consulate (Folder 32)
      - Employee registration form (Folder 33)
      - Middle East. Personnel (Folder 34)
      - Preliminary budget for United States, 1944 (Folder 35)
    - Fundusz Pomocy Kolezenskiej (Mutual Assistance Fund)
      - General (Folder 36)
      - Accounts
        - Expenditure (Folder 37)
        - Receipts (Folder 38)
      - Former employees
        - General (Folder 39)
        - List (Folder 40)
      - France (Box 296, Folder 1)
      - Ministry employees as prisoners of war (Folder 2)
      - Payments list (Folder 3)
      - Receipts (Folder 4)
    - Ministry
      - Annual report on activities (Folder 5)
      - Diplomatic course (Folder 6)
      - Employees in military service (Folder 7)
      - List of staff (Folder 8)
      - Military personnel in service of ministry (Folder 9)
      - Notes for minister (Folder 10)
      - Organizational scheme (Folder 11)
      - Typists (Folder 12)
    - Personnel issues (Folder 13)
    - Staff on leave